Rengoku…
Rengoku!
I…
I will fulfill my duty.
I will not allow anyone here to die!
Flame Breathing,
Esoteric Art!
Set your heart ablaze!
Rengoku!
Set your heart ablaze.
Rengoku…
MUGEN
Stop crying!
And you, stop leisurely passing out!
We're going to train!
I see.
Tanjiro did…
Don't run away, you coward!
Don't run away!
The Demon Slayer Corps
will always be fighting you demons
in the dark of the night
where you have the advantage!
Don't run away, you bastard!
You bastard! You coward!
Let's carry on Kyojuro's wish together.
IWAKAZU BOOKSTORE
He seems to be a clever boy.
Well, I was depressed
because we couldn't have a child,
but I'm relieved
since a good child came by.
Now we're happy
that our days have become enjoyable.
He's a kind boy.
He's even considerate to our servants.
He's so polite that it's hard
to believe he's still a child.
Even though we're not related by blood,
parents will always understand
their children.
I will let him succeed in my footsteps.
That makes me envious.
I would like to swap my son with yours.
He's really a good boy, but…
he has a skin disease.
He can't go outside during the daytime.
Oh, poor boy.
I think it would be great
if our company could make the cure.
As soon as possible.
I have come to make a report,
Lord Muzan.
Did you find the thing I asked for?
I did some investigations but
I did not find any reliable information.
I could not confirm its existence.
The Blue Spider Lily
is nowhere to be found.
So?
From now on, I will do my best
to live up to your expectations.
I have dealt with one of the Hashiras
as you ordered.
Please do not worry.
You seem to be
misunderstanding something, Akaza.
It's only a Hashira.
If you could kill a Hashira, so what?
It's only natural for demons
to defeat humans.
What I desire is the total annihilation
of the Demon Slayer Corps.
Eliminate every single one of them
so I won't see them ever again.
It shouldn't be complicated.
And yet, it still hasn't been achieved.
Can you explain it?
You proudly report
that you killed a Hashira,
but there were still
three demon hunters in that place.
Why didn't you deal with them?
I even took the trouble
to let you head there who was nearby.
Akaza.
Akaza!
I'm disappointed in you.
To think that you took a blow
from a swordsman who isn't a Hashira.
The Upper Rank Three has fallen.
Begone.
I heard a loud noise.
Are you okay?
You coward!
I remember your face, brat!
Next time we meet,
I'll blow your brains up!
Even Tanjiro gets depressed
and thinks he might be useless.
Well, of course.
Even someone who has a well-trained sound
like Rengoku ends up dying.
That kind of shock
could mess you up, I know.
Even Inosuke cried his heart out.
That must have been frustrating for him.
No matter how strong a person is,
they can still feel pain and sadness.
But we can't keep sitting around
all the time.
We have to strike our wounded spirits,
repeatedly, to get back up.
I'm sure that's what Rengoku would do.
Because I heard that sound from him.
It was a bit strange,
but he sounded strong and gentle.
Tanjiro, I sneaked you some buns.
Let's eat them!
Tanjiro is gone!
I'm so sorry, Zenitsu!
It's okay. I'm completely fine.
What's wrong?
But you don't seem to be fine!
I'm really so sorry!
-I can't find Tanjiro anywhere!
-It's okay.
He was training
even when his wounds hadn't healed yet,
so Miss Shinobu got angry!
Though I've told him to rest!
The wound in his stomach
was pretty deep, right?
Is he a fool?
Rengoku's crow…
Thank you for guiding me
to fulfill Rengoku's final wishes.
Are you Senjuro?
Have you heard
about Kyojuro Rengoku's obituary?
I was given messages
for your father and you from Kyojuro.
Thus, I'm here to tell the messages.
From my brother?
I already know what happened
to my brother.
Hey. Are you okay?
You look really pale.
Stop it!
I'm sure he left useless crap anyway.
It's because he became a swordsman
despite having no talent.
That's why he died.
Worthless!
Kyojuro is a foolish son!
People's abilities are determined
from the moment they're born.
Only a few people have talent,
the rest are just rabble.
They are just worthless rubbish.
Kyojuro was one of them.
He had no great talent.
That's the reason he ended up dead.
Senjuro, the funeral's over.
Don't make that pathetic face again!
Wait a second, sir.
That's a terrible thing to say.
Please stop talking that way!
Who are you?
Get out!
Don't step into my threshold!
I'm from the Corps.
You…
I see. You're…
the Sun Breathing user, right?
I'm sure you are!
Sun Breathing? What are you talking about?
He's so fast.
That wasn't the move of an amateur.
Father, please stop!
Please look at his face!
He's not feeling well!
Shut up! Silence!
That's enough, you bastard!
Just what have you been doing?
Not only insulting your son
who lost his life,
but even hitting your other son!
What do you want?
You're making fun of us, aren't you?
Why would you think that?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
That's a false accusation!
Because you're a Sun Breathing user.
I know those earrings.
It was written!
Could it be that by "Sun Breathing,"
he meant "Hinokami Kagura"?
The original breathing.
The first breathing ever created.
The godly technique.
All the other breathing techniques
are just derivatives of Sun Breathing.
Every other breathing is nothing more
than the imitation of Sun Breathing.
Those are just inferior copies
of Sun Breathing.
Fire, water, wind, all of them!
What does that mean?
My family has been charcoal burners
for generations.
We even have our family tree.
Sun Breathing…
Hinokami Kagura…
Wait.
There's something…
more important than that.
Don't get full of yourself just because
I said you're a Sun Breathing user, brat!
Why would I get full of myself?
Do you know how devastated I am
by my own weakness right now?
You…
shitty old man!
Watch out! My father is…
Don't speak ill of Rengoku!
…a former Hashira!
Please stop it, Father!
Why?
If Hinokami Kagura is the Sun Breathing,
why couldn't I save Rengoku back then?
Why?
Just why?
I've done it.
Here's the tea.
Yes, thank you.
I'm truly sorry
for headbutting your father.
Is he okay?
I think he'll be fine.
When he woke up, he went out to buy sake.
I see.
Thank you very much.
What?
I feel relieved.
I couldn't even talk back to him
when he spoke ill of my brother.
I wonder how
my brother's final moments were.
Is that so?
He fulfilled his duties until the end.
Thank you very much.
Oh, no, don't be like that.
I'm the one who's sorry
for not being of any help.
Please don't worry about it.
I'm sure that's what
my brother would have said.
I have an idea
which book my father used to read.
THE 21ST GENERATION
OF FLAME HASHIRA RECORD
I think this might be it.
Thank you very much.
Maybe it has something
that you want to know.
This is…
The pages are all torn up.
Most of them are unreadable.
Was it originally like this?
No, I don't think so.
The Generational Flame Hashira Record
is supposed to be preserved well.
I think my father tore it.
I'm very sorry.
Don't be. It's not your fault.
Please don't mind it.
You've come all this way,
but in the end, you've found nothing about
Hinokami Kagura and the Sun Breathing
that my father mentioned.
It's fine.
I know what I have to do.
I'll train harder.
Even though I know
how to unleash Hinokami Kagura,
I can't perform it perfectly.
Is that so?
When I unleash Hinokami Kagura
in Total Concentration state,
it's hard to move my body as I want.
So it's my problem.
My body can't catch up with my technique.
My physical strength has improved
with Total Concentration: Constant,
but it's still not enough.
If I could use it constantly,
my strength would improve day by day,
but it won't get me stronger
in an instant.
If only I had been stronger back then…
If only there was an instant way
to become strong enough to save Rengoku…
I've been thinking about it.
But there's no convenient way.
There are no shortcuts.
I have to struggle.
I have to move forward
with my best at the moment.
No matter how painful
or frustrating it might be.
I will definitely become a strong Hashira
like Kyojuro.
My brother never had a Tsuguko.
I should be his Tsuguko.
I had to heap up my achievements
as a reserve Hashira.
But…
my Nichirin Sword didn't change its color.
The color of Nichirin Swords won't change
until you have mastered
a certain level of swordsmanship.
No matter how much I practiced,
it was useless for me.
So I'm giving up being a swordsman.
I decided to help people in other ways.
It will break
the inheritance of Flame Hashiras
and make a scar in a long history.
But I believe my brother
will forgive me.
Please walk down the path
that you feel is right.
If anyone badmouths you,
I'll headbutt them!
Please don't.
I'll try to restore
the Generational Flame Hashira Record
and I'll look up other books, too.
I'll also try to ask my father.
I'll send a message via crow
when I find something.
I'm glad we were able to talk.
Please be careful on your way home.
With pleasure. Thank you very much.
One more thing, Tanjiro.
Please take it.
It's my brother's Nichirin Sword guard.
I can't accept something so valuable.
I…
I want you to take it.
I'm sure it will protect you.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
You're back.
About a while ago…
Shut up!
I don't care. Get out of here!
But Rengoku's…
Worthless!
It's probably just a grudge
against me anyway.
I know it.
Get out already!
Understood.
"Please take care of yourself."
Those were the only words he left for you.
I'm off, Father.
Kyojuro…
Am I getting a fever?
It hurts.
It's all right, Nezuko.
We'll arrive
at the Butterfly Mansion soon.
Ha…
Haganezuka?
How could you lose
your sword, you bastard?
You deserve to die!
You bastard deserve to die!
I'm sorry!
I am truly very sorry!
I've heard Haganezuka's chase
continued until nearly dawn.
That's why you've got no appetite?
Give it to me then!
Come here.
Thank you!
If Aoi and the others hadn't calmed him,
I think it would have gone until noon.
Do you want seconds?
-Want seconds?
Give it to me!
Thank you for yesterday, Aoi.
Thank you Sumi, Kiyo, and Naho, too.
It was not a big deal.
What's Haganezuka doing now?
Haganezuka is eating mitarashi dango
on the porch.
Somehow, he's in a better mood now.
Thank goodness.
Mitarashi dango is
Mr. Haganezuka's favorite food.
Buy him some of it when he gets angry.
I want to eat that too!
All right then, I'll buy it for you later.
Die!
I could die!
A hundred more.
It's been four months
since Rengoku's passing.
In between everyday training,
we followed orders we got from the crows,
and each of us went out to defeat demons.
-Be careful!
When Zenitsu went on a mission alone,
he no longer threw tantrums.
Give me a strand of Nezuko's hair.
I promise I'll do my best.
Inosuke is more assaulting
like a pig than before.
Run until your bones break!
Come on, you pip-squeak!
I think, not being alone…
We're almost there. Hang on!
-Nezuko!
-…is a blessing.
Nezuko!
North-northwest!
Defeat the demons hiding
in the mountain temple!
North-northwest!
Are you all right, Nezuko?
Are you getting wet because of the rain?
There should be demons around here.
Let's go, Nezuko!
Oh, no,
he's going to give us some trouble.
He's going down to the village.
Damn it.
What kind of demon hunter is he?
He's got a demon with him.
That's enough. Prepare yourself.
I'm sorry.
Don't underestimate me, brat!
Total Concentration,
Water Breathing, Fourth Form:
Striking Tide!
It's strange.
I'm pretty sure I heard a noise.
I'm so tired.
Nezuko, we're almost
at the Butterfly Mansion.
Please don't!
No!
Please let us, her and I, go!
-Please!
-So annoying! Just shut up!
Please don't!
Please let them go!
Kanao!
Missions. Orders. Shinobu.
Superiors. Aoi. Naho.
Hashira. Coin. Orders.
Coin!
Toss the coin to decide.
Follow your heart!
Kanao!
Miss Kanao!
Kanao…
-Miss Kanao…
Don't pull me so plainly.
You just received your orders, right?
Say something!
You are really a plain person!
Charge!
-Charge!
-What?
Hey! Cut it out, damn it!
What are you doing to the girls?
Let them go!
Wait. The girls are swarming him?
Is he--
Which is it?
It's a kidnapping! Please save them!
You dumb little brat!
Are you okay?
Yes!
You fool.
I'm the Great Tengen Uzui, a former ninja.
The man who is known as the most
flamboyant in these neighborhoods.
Did you think I would get headbutted
by a snotty brat like you?
Give Aoi and Naho back, you kidnapper!
Yes! That's right!
What are you planning to do?
Pervert!
You damn brats!
Who do you think you're talking to?
I'm your superior! A Hashira!
You damn little rascals!
I don't acknowledge you as a Hashira!
Don't you dare pout at me!
You don't acknowledge me, so what?
You lowly brat!
Is your brain completely dead?
I need female members on the mission,
so I'm bringing them along.
I don't need Kocho's permission
if they're not Tsugukos.
Naho isn't even a hunter!
Look! She isn't wearing a uniform!
I don't need her then.
What are you doing? You inhuman bastard!
He dropped me!
Anyway, I'm taking her to my mission.
I don't think she'll be useful,
but she's still our member regardless.
People have their own circumstances,
so I would like you
to stop poking around insensitively!
Let go of Aoi!
Dull.
You're so dull.
You guys are doing nothing,
and are plain here,
that's why the Corps is getting weaker.
We'll go in Aoi's stead.
"We"?
Who the hell are you?
What's your point?
I've just come back,
but I still have a lot of strength.
Ready to head out anytime.
Let go of Aoi!
I don't care if you're a muscle monster,
I'm not taking a step back.
Okay, then.
I'll have you guys come with me.
He's stepping down so easily.
But don't you dare defy me, brats!
Tanjiro…
He's huge.
So where are we going, Old Man?
The most flamboyant place in Japan
that's filled with lust and greed.
The Entertainment District,
where the demons live.
-Nin-nin!
CONGRATULATIONS ON THE BEGINNING
OF THE ENTERTAINMENT DISTRICT ARC!
Our part has finally started.
But are you guys sure
you're up for this mission?
I don't know you guys very well.
Go on, introduce yourselves!
Okay, let me start!
My name is Tanjiro Kamado.
Angelica sprout is my favorite.
She's Nezuko, my younger sister.
Kompeito is her favorite.
FAVORITE FOOD: KOMPEITO
My name is Zenitsu Agatsuma.
Sweet food is my favorite.
For example, a delightful unagi--
I didn't ask about your damn favorites!
I'm asking what you can do
to fight a demon!
The demons that lurk
in the Entertainment District are strong.
No!
I don't want to die! Really! No!
If you don't want to die, then fight.
I don't even want to meet strong demons!
I haven't done anything with Nezuko yet!
It's impossible for me!
Shut up for a minute!
I'm Inosuke Hashibira.
If you want to ask me,
you'll have to beat me first.
What the hell is this guy talking about?
What?
Let's move on to
the Taisho-era secret for today.
Let me tell you about myself.
I come from a family of ninjas.
That's why I lived a plain life
as a ninja, hiding in the shadows
when I was a child.
Really?
You're lying!
Don't lie to us.
It's not a lie!
The frustration of that time exploded, and
now I live as flamboyantly as possible.
Well, maybe I was born to be flamboyant.
You, too, have to show your flamboyance
on this mission to me.
I smell a strong sense
of responsibility from him.
He's someone you can trust.
What are you grinning for?
Next, episode 2,
"Entertainment District Infiltration."
You guys have to do your job well!
-Yes!
TO BE CONTINUED